BENJAMIN DAHL

853 Skeel Dr. Camarillo, CA 93010 (218) 684-1160 bdahl1@liberty.edu

Experienced Web Developer with 7+ years' experience in front-end design and 3+ years' experience in back-end web application development. Experience across a broad range of information technology including Linux server management, systems development, network design and implementation, and I.T. support. Working both professionally and as a freelancer I've worked closely with clients to understand their needs and requirements and to deliver business solutions on top of beautiful and well coded websites.

Professional Experience

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER, CAMARILLO, CA

Website Design & Development, September 2011 – Present

• Designed and developed over 30+ websites for more than 20+ satisfied clients using WordPress, Django, and Joomla including custom WordPress theme and plugin development.

ASSOCIATION FREE LUTHERAN BIBLE SCHOOL, PLYMOUTH, MN

Web Developer & Administrator, March 2010 - May 2011, April 2013 - August 2017

- Designed and developed two major redesigns of aflbs.org increasing traffic and potential student leads.
- Designed and developed two internal reporting applications using AngularJS, Google Maps API, PHP, and MySQL.
- Integrated payment gateway APIs and developed over two dozen secure web forms for collecting information and payments.

OAKS CHRISTIAN SCHOOLS, WESTLAKE VILLAGE, CA

Systems Technician, September 2012 - September 2014

- Provided systems support for Windows Server 2003/2008/2012, Unix BSD, Linux, Cisco IP Tel systems, Cisco networking, Citrix, PC hardware & software, and systems documentation.
- Developed an internal Dropbox web application using PHP for students to submit homework assignments.
- Worked with Director of Communications to make improvements to website and developed a mobile friendly video e-Card html page.

BRISTOL BAY TELEPHONE COOPERATIVE, KING SALMON, AK

Inside/Outside Plant Technician, June 2012 - August 2012

KAKN RADIO, NAKNEK, AK

Radio Station Engineer, June 2011 – August 2011, June 2012 – August 2012

Education

LIBERTY UNIVERSITY, LYNCHBURG, VA

2015 - 2017

 B.S. Business Management Information Systems – Web Development Summa Cum Laude – Delta Mu Delta Honor Society

MOORPARK COLLEGE, MOORPARK, CA

2012 - 2015

Major in Computer Science for transfer
Enthusiastic Programmers Club – Studied 3 years of C++, Calculus, Physics, and Data Structures & Algorithms

Skills & Accomplishments

- Skilled in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, Python, C++, and Responsive Web Design.
- Experienced using WordPress, Bootstrap, uiKit, jQuery, AngularJS, XCode, Visual Studio, Git, Linux, Bash, Photoshop, Illustrator, and Dreamweaver.
- Grand prize winner at Code for the Kingdom Hackathon, San Francisco, 2016 for Wechat chat-bot written in Python.
- Technical Merit award winner at Code for the Kingdom Hackathon, Los Angeles, 2015 for VR app in ThreeJS.
- Intermediate Brazilian Portuguese
- General class Ham Radio License KL3IM
- Board member Bay Broadcasting Company, Inc. 2017
- Eagle Scout Award 2009